{"tossups": [{"question": "This leader was in charge during a namesake affair involving the merger of helicopter companies Sikorsky and Westland. Roy Walsh was used as Patrick Magee\u2019s pseudonym to perpetrate an event that nearly killed this person. This politician successfully handled a strike led by Arthur Scargill and (*) mineworkers. This politician presided over a war that saw the Sun publish the headline \"Gotcha\" after the sinking of the ARA General Belgrano. After cutting a free milk program, this politician was nicknamed the \"Milk Snatcher.\" The Provisional IRA targeted this prime minister in the Brighton Hotel bombing. For 10 points, name this conservative British prime minister, nicknamed the \"Iron Lady.\"", "answer": "Margaret Hilda Thatcher", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "These figures title a poem that coined the phrase \"no longer at ease\" and begins \"A cold coming we had of it.\" That poem, describing the \"Journey\" of these figures, is by T.S. Eliot. A story titled for these figures describes a mailbox reading \"D\" instead of \"Dillingham\" in front of a flat with rent \"at $8 per week.\" In that story, a character claims to \"look like a Coney Island chorus girl\" after visiting Madame (*) Sofronie's. That story begins with a wife counting a dollar and eighty-seven cents, which is not enough to replace a strap that her husband Jim uses in place of a watch chain. For 10 points, name these figures who partly title an O. Henry Christmas story about the \"gift\" of these figures.", "answer": "Magi [accept synonyms like Wise Men or Three Kings; accept Journey of the Magi or Gift of the Magi]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In this country, the X-Seed 4000 was a hypothetical skyscraper with 800 floors. The Gate Tower Building in this country has a highway through part of its floors. It\u2019s not the U.S, but a \"Rainbow Bridge\" crosses a bay in this country\u2019s capital. This country\u2019s namesake sea contains Sado Island and the Golden Horn Bay. This country\u2019s capital contains a building called the (*) \"Skytree.\" The \"suicide forest\" is near a mountain in this country, which disputes the Kuril Islands with Russia. This country\u2019s bullet train network is called the \"Shinkansen,\" and its island of Honshu features Mount Fuji. For 10 points, name this country with cities such as Kyoto and Tokyo.", "answer": "Japan [accept Nihon-koku or Nippon-koku]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "This element is used in the crystal bar process to purify metals like titanium or zirconium. This element\u2019s compound with hydrogen interconverts with water to drive the production of acetic acid in the Monsanto and Cativa processes. This element is usually titrated against sodium thiosulfate. A (*) clock reaction commonly used as a kinetics demonstration relies on the deep blue-black color this element makes when complexed with starch. This element\u2019s salt with silver serves as an effective ice nucleation site, making it useful for cloud seeding. This element, named for its purple vapor, is necessary for the production of thyroid hormones. For 10 points, name this heaviest stable halogen, with atomic symbol I.", "answer": "iodine [prompt on I before mention]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In this painting, a set of medallions depict scenes from the Passion of Christ. A carved figure in this painting is believed to depict Saint Margaret. A cherry tree is barely visible through an open window in this painting. One theory about this painting focuses on the detail that one figure\u2019s hair is not down, but instead kept in a (*) headdress. Some scholars analyze the meaning of this painting\u2019s depiction of one figure using his left hand to grasp another figure\u2019s right hand. A dog representing fidelity stands in this painting\u2019s foreground. In this painting\u2019s background, an orange sits on the windowsill and a convex mirror reflects its two main figures. For 10 points, name this painting of a couple by Jan van Eyck.", "answer": "Arnolfini Portrait [accept The Arnolfini Wedding, The Arnolfini Marriage, or Portrait of Giovanni Arnolfini and his Wife]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: Description acceptable. A memorial for people who died on one of these events is located at Observation Hill. Henry Bowers took a famous photo during an ill-fated one of these events, where three people were buried with a cross made out of skis. The leader of one of these events hid his plans from his crew and the owner of his ship Fram, Fridtjof Nansen (\"frayed-jov non-sin\"), until he'd already left, saying he had taken a \"slight detour.\" During one of these events, Lawrence Oates died after stating that he was \"just going outside and may be some time.\" The (*) \"Nimrod\" one of these events climbed Mount Erebus and all of the crew died on the \"Terra Nova\" one. Ernest Shackleton, Roald Amundsen, and Robert Falcon Scott all led, for 10 points, what missions to the southernmost continent?", "answer": "expeditions to Antarctica [accept South Pole in place of \"Antarctica\"; accept obvious equivalents and descriptions like Antarctic expeditions; prompt on specific missions and expeditions alone with \"What place were they trying to reach\"; prompt on answers only mentioning a pole]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Two characters created by this author play a game that forbids \u201cstatements\u201d and \u201crepetitions\u201d that uses tennis scoring. A table in one of this author\u2019s plays seats items like the tortoises Plautus and Lightning from two different time periods as the play goes on. Characters in another play by this author play Questions. One of this author\u2019s plays opens with a genius asking her tutor (*) Septimus Hodge about \"carnal embrace.\" In this man\u2019s most famous play, actors emerging from a ship\u2019s barrels reveal themselves as Tragedians, who the Player led in performing The Murder of Gonzago. That play opens with 92 coin flips all turning up heads. For 10 points, name this author of Arcadia and Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead.", "answer": "Sir Tom Stoppard [accept Tomas Straussler]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The second derivative of this quantity equals the time-averaged potential energy plus two times the time-averaged kinetic energy by the virial theorem. The intermediate principal value of this quantity corresponds to unstable motion when it differs from the other two principal values, a result known as the (*) Dzhanibekov (\"JIN-uh-BECK-ove\") effect. This quantity equals the volume integral of r-squared dm. Adding a factor of m times d squared to this quantity gives its value around a parallel axis. When this value is multiplied by angular velocity, the result is angular momentum. For 10 points, name this rotational analog of mass symbolized I.", "answer": "moment of inertia [accept rotational inertia or inertia tensor; do NOT accept or prompt on \"inertia\" alone]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of this religion\u2019s hymns references a passage of the Book of Abraham that describes the star Kolob as the nearest star to God. In this religion, young men aged 12 - 18 are known as \"deacons,\" \"teachers,\" and \"priests,\" and are holders of the lesser Aaronic priesthood as opposed to the greater Melchizedek (\"mel-chuh-ZEH-duhk\") priesthood. This religion\u2019s \"Plan of Salvation\" claims that humans will be divided into Celestial, Terrestrial, and Telestial kingdoms of glory. This religion\u2019s (*) \"Word of Wisdom\" forbids drinking alcohol or smoking tobacco, and its first prophet is believed to have been given Golden Plates by the Angel Moroni. For 10 points, name this Christian religion founded in 1830 by Joseph Smith.", "answer": "The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints [or LDS church; accept Mormonism]", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "A composer with this surname dedicated their Three Romances for Violin and Piano to Joseph Joachim (\"YO-uh-kim\"). Another composer with this surname possibly titled a symphony after an Adolf Bottger poem, and wrote a symphony whose opening theme was based on a landler. That symphony includes a \"Lebhaft\" (\"LAYb-huft\") first movement and a (*) \"cathedral\" movement. One composer with this surname included \"Traumerei\" (\"trow-meh-ray\") in his Scenes From Childhood. For 10 points, what surname was shared by a German piano virtuoso who popularized performing from memory and the composer of the Spring and Rhenish symphonies, Clara and Robert respectively?", "answer": "Schumann [accept Clara Josephine Schumann or Robert Schumann]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The New Zealand ship Talune worsened this event\u2019s impact in Western Samoa. This event\u2019s first emergence in the US was at Fort Riley, Kansas. Governor John Martin Poyer\u2019s blockade stopped this event from impacting American Samoa. The Philadelphia Liberty Loans Parade held during this event led to widespread deaths. This event\u2019s (*) colloquial name was partly taken from its impact on King Alfonso XIII (\"the thirteenth\"). A precaution during this event, which was dubbed the \"purple death,\" was opposed by the Anti-Mask League of San Francisco. For 10 points, name this pandemic caused by an H1N1 virus at the end of WWI and often named for a neutral Iberian nation.", "answer": "1918 Flu pandemic [or Spanish flu pandemic; or Spanish influenza pandemic; prompt on partial answers]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: Specific term required. Prince of Wales Island and Admiralty Island are off one of these geographic features. Palo Duro Canyon and Lake Meredith are near a city on one of these features, Amarillo. The first Spanish settlement in the continental US, Pensacola, is on one of these features. The city of Cumberland is on another of these features, and the Fort Henry Bridge crosses the Ohio River at Wheeling, which is on one of these features. The easternmost town in (*) West Virginia, Harpers Ferry, is on one of these features. Maryland has one of these features that at some points is only about two miles wide. The three westernmost counties of Oklahoma are on one of these features. For 10 points, what protrusions are named after a part of cookware?", "answer": "panhandles [prompt on descriptive answers with \"what is the term called\"; anti-prompt on specific panhandles; do NOT accept or prompt on \"peninsulas\"]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "This band hid clues in a video of TV static that sent fans on an internet scavenger hunt. A song by this band confesses \"Michael\u2019s gone insane / Julie starts to make me nervous\" and later asks \"would you be my little quarantine?\"Another song by this band admits \"I wish I didn\u2019t have to rhyme / every time I sang.\" The narrator of that song by this band wants to (*) \"turn back time, to the good ol\u2019 days,\" and repeats that his name is \"Blurryface.\" This band included \"Shy Away\" on their most recent album, Scaled and Icy. Another song by this band claims \"I\u2019m falling, so I\u2019m taking my time on [the title journey].\" For 10 points, name this band that wrote \"Level of Concern,\" \"Stressed Out,\" and \"Ride,\" named for a number of airmen.", "answer": "Twenty One Pilots", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "In a short story by this author, the decree that chance should intervene in every aspect of the title drawing is made by the Company. Another story by this author ends with Juan Dahlmann dying in a knife fight on the plains. The narrator of one story by this author finds references to fictional worlds within the Anglo-American Cyclopaedia\u2019s pages. In addition to \"The (*) South,\" this author wrote a story describing Purifiers\u2019 search for a Crimson structure and an omnipotent Book Man. This creator of Tlon suggested the title structure is \"unlimited but periodic\" in its array of infinite books in infinite hexagonal rooms. For 10 points, name this Argentinian author whose collection Ficciones includes \"The Library of Babel.\"", "answer": "Jorge Luis Borges", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Members of this phylum use a set of cuticular (\"CUTE-tick-you-lur\") plates known as a \"grinder\" to break down food within their sucking pharynxes (\"FAIR-INK-z\"). The toxin Subtilisin (\"SUB-tih-sill-in\") is used to paralyze these organisms by the fungus A. Oligospora (\"OGE-lee-oh-spore-uh\"), which obtains nitrogen by capturing these organisms in hyphal (\"high-fall\") \"nets.\" The gene daf-2 (\"d-a-f two\") has been linked to one member of this phylum\u2019s growth-arrested \"dauer\" (\"DOWER\") stage. That member of this phylum was used as a model organism by (*) Sydney Brenner, and was the first organism to have its entire genome sequenced. In addition to C. Elegans, this phylum also includes the parasitic pinworms and hookworms. For 10 points, name this phylum of roundworms.", "answer": "Nematoda [accept nematodes; accept roundworms before mention; prompt on worms]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A scandal in this state involved the company FirstEnergy and a speaker of this state\u2019s house, Larry Householder. Donald Trump\u2019s first rally since leaving office was in this state. Joe Biden\u2019s Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, Marcia Fudge, is from this state. One politician from this state was rejected from a January 6th commission, that politician is Jim (*) Jordan. Rob Portman serves with Sherrod Brown as senator from this state.. Donald Trump called for a boycott of Goodyear, which is based in this state\u2019s city of Akron. Mike DeWine succeeded John Kasich (\"KAY-sick\") as governor of this state. For 10 points, name this state with capital Columbus and the city Cleveland.", "answer": "Ohio", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "In one work, this thinker applied Kant\u2019s idea of \"radical evil\" to those describing the oppressed as \"superfluous people.\" That work contrasts regimes using terror only against political opponents and those using it against the masses. This thinker claimed one figure showed an \"inability to think\" by answering questions with \"stock phrases\" and misinterpreting the categorical imperative. Nazism and Stalinism were analyzed in this thinker\u2019s The Origins of (*) Totalitarianism. In her most famous work, this thinker claimed its central figure was not driven by \"insane hatred\" or \"indoctrination,\" instead demonstrating the \"banality of evil.\" For 10 points, which thinker analyzed a Nazi party member at his trial in Eichmann in Jerusalem?", "answer": "Hannah Arendt", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "Wealthy women like Alva Belmont and Anne Morgan who supported a strike after this event were known as the \"mink brigade.\" Max Steuer (\"sh-toy-er\") destroyed the credibility of Kate Alterman\u2019s testimony on this event after she repeated it verbatim many times. The ILGWU and Clara Lemlich led the Uprising of the 20,000 in the aftermath of this event, which was investigated by Francis (*) Perkins. Stairway doors that could only open inwards caused people to jump to their deaths during this event. Max Blanck and Isaac Harris owned part of the Asch Building where this event happened. For 10 points, name this 1911 tragedy that resulted in the deaths of 123 women in a New York City garment factory.", "answer": "Triangle shirtwaist factory fire [prompt on answers mentioning a fire at the Asch building before mention; prompt on answers mentioning a general disaster not specifying fire; prompt on partial answers]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Permanent examples of these things have Max-Age or Expires attributes to prevent them from remaining indefinitely, although their \"zombie\" examples avoid that by automatically recreating themselves when they\u2019re deleted. Session hijacking refers to stealing these things to impersonate a user. The (*) authentication type of these things are used to keep an account logged in as it navigates different pages of a site. The GDPR requires websites to get consent for these things, resulting in pop-ups asking the user to allow them. For 10 points, name these pieces of information stored by the browser, named for a type of baked good.", "answer": "cookies [or HTTP cookies; accept magic cookies; accept session cookies]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One character in this work remarks that a nobleman and art collector he meets must be \"the happiest of mortals, for he is above everything he possesses.\" That character from this work refuses to enter England after seeing an execution at sea based on Admiral Byng\u2019s, staged \"to encourage the others.\" Red sheep from (*) El Dorado are given to Cacambo and this work\u2019s title character, who survives the Lisbon earthquake. This novella ends with the line \"We must cultivate our garden.\" This novella\u2019s title character leaves Baron Thunder-Ten-Tronckh\u2019s castle to travel with Cunegonde and the tutor Dr. Pangloss. For 10 points, name this novella satirizing the idea that \"all is for the best in the best of all possible worlds,\" written by Voltaire.", "answer": "Candide; or, Optimism [accept Candide; ou, l\u2019Optimisme]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": []}